TALHI MOHAMMED

Anassi 8 E 13 N 125 , Casablanca, Maroc - 20630.

(+212) 659889493

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohammed-talhi-3b4bb21a4/

talhimohammed507@gmail.com



OBJECTIVE OVERVIEW

I'm a young Moroccan 23 years old, currently in my second year Master's degree in Internet of Things, Software and Analytics at the National School of Computer Science and Systems Analysis (ENSIAS - RABAT).

I'm rigorous in everything I undertake and I am passionate about Java technologies (Java EE / DevOps / Spring Boot / Microservices / React Js) .

EDUCATION

➤ 2019-2021 : Specialized MASTER at National School of Computer Science and Systems Analysis (ENSIAS - RABAT) .

Option: Internet of Things, Software and Analytics

2018-2019 : Bachelor Degree in Sciences and Techniques at the Faculty of Sciences and Techniques. Option : Computer science and Networks.

> 2016-2018 : Diplôme d'Etudes Universitaire en Sciences et Techniques (DEUST)

Option: Mathematics, Computer Science Physics

> 2015-2016: Faculty of sciences BENMSIK

Option: Physical Science Chemistry Mathematics.

> 2014-2015: High school diploma in Experimental Sciences.

Option: Physical Science.

WORK EXPERIENCE

- > from 20-01-2016 to 20-07-2016: End of Studies Internship(Bachelor's degree).
 - Development of a desktop application for monitoring productivity in information system consulting projects.
 - Tools: Java 1.8, Swing, Java mail Api, MySQL.
- > from 01-07-2017 to 01-08-2017 : Web development Internship .
 - Development of a web application for stock management
 - tools: PHP, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, MySQL.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Development of an Android Application for Health Care .

Tools: Firebase, Google Could Platform (Google API Direction), Java 1.8, XML, Java Mail API, Android Studio, Junit 5 (Unit tests)

- Development of an intelligent agriculture system based on the Internet of Things. (In progress)
 - This project is supervised by HELIANTHA company.
- Development of an application allowing the management and follow-up of graduation projects (In progress)
 - Tools: React JS, Spring boot, Spring Data, Spring Security, PostgresSQL.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- COVID-19 TRACKER (Android Application) .
 - Tools: Android studio, Java, XML, Retrofit Java.
- CRUD API for managing COURSES.
 - Tools: Spring boot, Spring DATA JPA, Hibernet, Derby.

KNOWLEDGE

- Programming Languages : C, Java , Matlab , Python , SQL , XML .
- Machine Learning: Regression, KNN, KDD, Arbre de decision, Clustering.
- Web technologies: PHP, HTML5, CSS3, Java Script, React Js, Spring boot, Selenium WEB, JSF, Hibernet.
- Software : Docker , JUnit , TestNG
- SGBD: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Derby.
- System design : Merise et UML.
- > Software architecture: Design Patterns , (OOD) Object Oriented Design .
- Project management : SCRUM .
- Operating system: Windows, Linux (ubuntu).
- Others: Networks, UX design, Image, text, sound processing...
- Microsoft OFICE: Word, Excel, PowerPoint.

CERTIFICATES

- Front-End Web Development with React from The Hong Kong University Of Science And Technology (Coursera)
- Agile Software Development offered by The UNIVERSITY OF MINNESOTA (Coursera).
- Deep Learning from deeplearning.ai (Coursera).
- Object Oriented Design & Design Patterns offered by THE UNIVERSITY OF ALBERTA (Coursera).
- Machine Learning with python by IBM.
- Enterprise Design Thinking Co-Creator Badge from IBM.

LANGUAGES

- > Arabic .
- > French.
- > English.

HOBBIES & INETERSESTS

- Watching movies, listening to music, reading books, and travel .